

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Technical Specialist seeking roles in System Administration, Configuration Management, Patch Management, Software Troubleshooting, Cloud Computing, Performance Tuning, Server Monitoring, Software Installation, Service Management, VMWare, Servicenow, Python

Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Sc [Computers]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Designation: Technical Speadist Current Company: HCL Technologies

Pref. Location: Saudi Arabia, Chennai, Dubai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Tech Support Engnr

Current Location: Chennai

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technical Specialist, Tech Support Engineer, System Administration, Configuration Management, Patch Management, Software Troubleshooting, Cloud Computing, Performance Tuning, Server Monitoring, Software Installation, Service Management, VMWare, Servicenow, Python

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

10+ years of experience specialized in UNIX System Administration working on server-based operating system; kernel configurations on Red hat Linux, Cent OS, and Esxi servers, Networking, kernel Parameter & Tuning, Trouble Shooting System & Performance Issues, Package Management and Patch Management. Extensive experience in installation, conguration and administration of, Redhat 7.2/6.7/5.11, Extensive implementation and troubleshooting experience under Client Server Systems.

Work Experience

- HCL Technologies as Technical Speaclist Nov 2017 to Till Date
 - ? Supporting over 25K+ Linux Servers & Aix servers.
 - ? Managing servers in verious environment like Production, Development and Testing in the project
 - ? Performing VMWare clients vmotion and storage vmotion to eliminate application downtime from planned server maintenance by migrating running virtual machines between Clusters
 - ? Working knowledge on storage and host migration from different clusters using VMware thin client.
 - ? Taking snapshot of VM?s for Application upgrade per customer requirment.
 - ? Building virtual servers with OVA Templet on VMware.
 - ? Responsible for creating and configuring Virtual Machines and Clusters on VMware Esxi host according to Customer requirement.
- ? Working knowledge on Service Now (Change Management) tool to provide all kind of support.
- ? Install, Configure & Manage applications like Redhat Satellite Server.
- ? Performing Quaterly Patching activities on Redhat servers using Satellite service.
- ? Create and extend Veritas Filesystem based on customer requirment.
- ? Configuring Oracle RAC cluster based on application team requirement.
- Perfoming pymoves activites for physical servers storage migration.
- ? Monitoring HBA paths for physical servers.
- ? Managing physical servers on HPE one view.
- ? Creating and assigning profile for new build physical server using HPE one view.
- ? Monitor Disk space and space as needed in LVMSetup and administration of VERITAS Volume Manager and HA Clusters.
- ? Upgrading HP Blade servers ILO from GEN8 to GEN9.
- ? Written few Shell scripts for Application related upgrades and patching.
- ? Managing the file systems with LVM to Create, extend, Reduce & mounting file systems.
- ? Hands-on experience in monitoring server performance like memory, load, disk space, analyzing server slowness & monitoring active & in-active jobs.
- ? Providing Remote Support for phyliscal servers via ILO, IDRAC, BMC and Qunta.
- ? Raising vendor support case for RCA
- ? Responsible for providing RCA to the Problem Incidents.

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Virtusa Polaris as Technical Consultant

Apr 2015 to Nov 2017

- Worked on Clarify Bridge (Incident Management) ticketing tool to provide all kind of support. Worked on BT (British Technology) cloud portal.
- Responsible for creating and configuring Virtual Machines and Clusters on Cloud Compute Environment according to Customer requirement.
- Taking snapshot of volumes for back up purpose.
- Configuring WAN, LAN, TCP/IP,VPN, networking and load balancing on cloud portal as per the customer requirement.
- Environment maintenance and monitoring through Nagios as well Custom Shell Scripts for traps on OS. Troubleshooting Linux File systems Corruption and Recovery of File systems.

- Checking of CPU Utilization, Memory usage, Disk I/o and Network traffic through checkMk monitoring tool.

 Managing Virtual memory, adding additional swap space as needed.

 Creating, extending & mounting file systems. Managing the file systems with LVM & Disk Management extend, Reduce.
- Configuring installing and upgrading the packages using RPM and YUM
- Configuration of YUMrepository and package management with YUM
- Configuring FTP, NFS, SAWBA and maintain user accessibility on live server.
- Responsible for providing RCA to the Problem Incidents.
- User administration on Unix/Linux Environments.
- Responsible for packaging various Applications according to Project requirement.

Symbiotic Info Tech Pvt, Ltd as System Engineer

Aug 2010 to Apr 2015

- Installed and configured all the Linux servers in the network as per specifications of clients
- Configuring the production servers and application in Nagios Monitor.
- Installing, configuring applications such as apache and tomcat.
- User and group administration and SUDO user's configuration.
- Partition of Disk, Creating new file system, mounting them and changing to fstab.
- Knowledge of Configuring and Managing Hardware Raid level 0, 1, and 5.
- Daily activities include creating/modifying user accounts, password administration and Security.
- Implementation of security policies using ACL, Selinux and firewall. Provided Support in Apache Servers, Samba, Nfs, Ftp.

- Provided Support in Apache Servers, Samua, Nis, rtp.

 Configuring and monitoring Disk mirroring, striping using LVM.

 Monitoring & troubleshooting with performance related issues.

 Troubleshoot server hardware failure and co-ordinate with respective vendors to resolve the issue.

 Managing servers using Remote Management Tools like DRAC and IMM.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Madras University in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Redhat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) Redhat Certified Engineer (RHCE) AWS (Certified Solution Architect - Associate)

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Red Hat Linux/Ubuntu, Sun Solaris	
HP-UX & Windows	
Shell, Perl & Python Basics	
British Telecom cloud, Microsoft Azure	
VMWare, KVM, Oracle Virtual Box, Hyper-V	
HP Blades, HP RMS, Dell, EMC VNX	
Iptables, Sonic Firewall	
SVN	
Sensu, Nagios, HPOM, Zabbix	
veritas volume manger	
Rundeck	
Service-now, RTC, HPSA, Clarify Bridge	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.